

Muhammad Alyan

Software Engineer

I am a software engineer currently studying at Nust University Pakistan. Highly driven by the modern trends of technology, I am striving for learning more experiences while working in a competitive environment. Ambitious for collaborating with leading computer engineers.

alyanbutt1000@gmail.com

🔾 🛮 Islambad, Pakistan

github.com/MUHAMMADALYAN

+923056296846

in linkedin.com/in/alyan1

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Software EngineeringNust Pakistan

08/2018 - Present Islamabad

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fiverr

Level 1 Seller (2020-Present)

I work as a part-time freelancer on Fiverr. I provide tech solutions like solving programming tasks, web development, automation, scraping, machine learning and data science projects.

Public New York City Project Lead Panic (2020-Present)

I worked for Public New York City .I developed analytic platform Panic using Tensorflow and flask for web app. PANIC is a perceptive diagnostic for evaluating brands and developing communications strategy and tactics.

Intern

Sigma Lab (2019-2020)

Working under the direct supervision of Dr Hassan Aqeel Khan on different machine learning web applications. Previously developed sentimental analysis and NLP systems

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Panic Platform (2019 - Present)

Developed analytic platform Panic for PUBLIC NEW YORK CITY. Brand PANIC is a perceptive diagnostic for evaluating brands and developing communications strategy and tactics. By analyzing the five core elements of the brand, PUBLIC helps clients understand where they stand and what they stand for. The patented process highlights brand strengths, isolates areas of underachievement and sets benchmarks for brand growth.

Clozet (2020 - 2021)

Pakistan first shopping app that lets you to shop from all favourite brands in one place. It display products of all brands of specific category item and solve the problem to search specific product by going to different brands websites

Covid-19 Trends Prediction (2020 - 2021)

Used my machine learning and data science skills to predict the spread of COVID-19 and required time for its eradiction. I used Sklearn and Seaborn for getting better accuracy and minimum loss.

Trendy (2019 - 2020)

Developed an e-commerce website for semester project with my team members in which the technologies used were PHP, HTML, CSS, bootstrap and SQL.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development Machine Learning

Scraping and Automation Database

Azure Deep Learning

Django,Flask Tensorflow, Pytorch

React JS

Java Python

CERTIFICATIONS

TensorFlow Developer Professional Certificate

Machine Learning Stanford University

Deeplearning Specialization

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Google Cloud Fest

IT team member. I worked with the IT team to organize various tech workshops and seminars .

Jazz SDG Hackathon

Part of the organizing committee. Organized a three-day hackathon with the collaboration of leading computer engineers and industry people.

Google Dev Fest

Organized workshops on different teach concepts

ACHIEVEMENTS

Fiverr Seller 1

Kaggle Top 10 percent

LANGUAGES

Fnalish Urdu

Full Professional Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Web Technologies

Computer Vision

NLP